EMILY HANNAN

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

■ emilyhannan@gmail.com
 ehannan.herokuapp.com

in linkedin.com/in/emilyhannan hannan-emily

Technical Summary

Designer of immersive applications with creative, responsive designs. I'm a proactive, team centred developer who works well in broader multi-disciplinary teams. Experienced in Agile environments, I create efficient, on-time products. With a background in design, creative content, immersive drawing installations and sculpture, I develop experiential, feeling applications.

 Languages
 CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Python, SQL, JSX, EJS

 Frameworks
 Django, React, Redux, Node.js, Express

 Libraries
 jQuery, bcrypt, Materialize, Bootstrap

 Databases
 MongoDB, Mongoose, PostgreSQL, Sequelize

 Design
 Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Web Fonts

Other AJAX, Agile, Git, Git Hub, Heroku, RESTful routing, CRUD, Pair Programming

Education

Web Development Immersive General Assembly, 2018 Seattle, WA

Master of Fine Arts, Sculpture Cranbrook Academy of Art, 2012 Bloomfield Hills, MI

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Sculpture University of Washington, 2010 Seattle, WA

Project Highlights

Mood Tracker GROUP

Python, Django, Materialize Chart your mood by analysing your selfies! A responsive Python/Django app, we utilized the Amazon Facial Rekognition machine learning API, Charts.js and Materialize to generate an image-rich tracker of each user's mood, by their selfies. I developed all front end components in Django & Materialize, with a major emphasis on clean, responsive UI. I acted as GitMaster and Project Manager to ensure our product met the required standards within our time frame.

Apocalyprep GROUP

React, Redux, MongoDB, Mongoose NOAA API, React-Materialize A comprehensive, real time emergency prep and severe weather alert app. Built as a responsive, image-rich application in React with Redux. I built the MongoDB schema, Mongoose routing and all front end styling including implementing React-Materialize. I compiled custom emergency prep content from multiple Canadian and US disaster relief agencies, and built a seeder object to populate a master "supply list" database. I acted as the Project Manager.

PNW Overland

INDIVIDUAL Node.js, EJS, Express, PostgreSQL, Google Maps API, bcrypt, Materialize An interactive Node.js app, serving as an exploration guide to Pacific Northwest backcountry offroading trails. Featuring interactive custom Google Map API calls, responsive imagery and embedded auto-play video. The app integrates Google Map APIs, curated dash cam videos, community guides and user functionality to save favourite trails and leave notes for other users. Pair programmed with team members to solve database and routing challenges.

Chasing Carmen SanDiego INDIVIDUAL

INDIVIDUAL HTML5 Canvas, JS, jQuery, Materialize A delightfully fun HTML5 Canvas trivia based game, pitting two users against that international thief, Carmen SanDiego. I designed custom graphics and UI elements for a responsive user experience. Players interact with witnesses as canvas obstacles, and if they answer enough questions right - they've found Carmen!

Experience

Web Development Immersive

General Assembly, Seattle, WA

Jan - April 2018

A 3-month, 60+ hrs/week, project-based web development accelerator. Educated in popular web technologies, database development, CRUD, RESTful routing, Git and version control. Practiced pair-programming, Agile development, wire-framing, rapid prototyping, and peer code review.

Graphic Designer

Black Press, Saanich, BC

Oct 2017 - Jan 2018

Responsible for layout, graphics and advertising design for a twice weekly newspaper. Designed 20+ digital advertising graphics for responsive web and mobile applications per week. Optimized content for Google SEO keywords. Content strategy and design for a range of retail, ecommerce, outdoor sports, grocery and food service clients.

Graphic Designer

May - Oct 2017

Media One, Victoria, BC

UX/UI design, planning and strategy for a wide range of clients, including a marine suspensions seating manufacturer, food delivery app, fishing charter tours, and a restaurant management app. Digital advertising graphic design, optimized for Google Adword placement. Campaign asset design for desktop, mobile, print and industry conference deliverables.

Co-Founder

May 2016 - May 2017

The Little Red Backpack, Victoria, BC

Founded a Social Media Consulting Company. Content graphic design, brand strategy and logo design. Designed content strategy development plans, including content maps, brand imaging guidelines and community response plans.

Marketing Coordinator & Designer July 2015 - May 2017

Capital Iron, Victoria, BC

Sole advertising designer for large corporate retailer. Annual advertising budget over \$300,000 with over one million in annual sales. Creative strategy planning and graphic design for web, mobile and print media. Primary social media and community manager.